

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211







DevOps Engineer seeking roles in System Administration, Client Relationship Management, Data Management, Change Management, Scripting Languages, Server Health Monitoring, Continuous Delivery Pipeline, Continuous Deployment, Project Support



Current Designation: DevOps Engineer

levOps Engineer Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 2 Month(s)
enrich Technologies Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Company: Netenrich Technologies
Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad

Highest Degree: B.Sc [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Tech Support Engnr

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: DevOps Engineer, Tech Support Engineer, System Administration, Client Relationship Management, Data Management, Change Management, Scripting Languages, Server Health Monitoring, Continuous Delivery

Pipeline, Continuous Deployment, Project Support

Verified : Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 19-Jan-21 Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education |

Summary

Afocused professional with over 5 years of experience in Devops engineer including of configuration management, automation of java J2EE application builds, provisioning the environments on Linux and windows, continuous integration and continuous delivery processes

Exposure of principles and Software Configuration Management (SCM) in Agile Scrum

Executed environment setup on development, QA environments and managed the automated deployments using scripts

Experience in Docker Kubernetes build scaling and monitoring the services and GITLAB

Expertise in monitoring the environments and troubleshooting the issues on application from the orchestration engine Jenkins and experienced in installation and configuration application servers tomcat and automated deployment process using python scripting and shell scripting automation

Performed on Jenkins pipeline using build pipeline plugins and supported Windows and Linux environments

Work Experience

Netenrich Technologies as DevOps Engineer

Aug 2016 to Till Date

Growth Path:

Application Support Engineer 2016-2017

DevOps Engineer 2017-Present

Project Executed: Title: OPSRAMP

Period: Dec'17-Present

Team Size: 5

Description: OpsRamp is a cloud-based IT operations management platform that brings together on-premises and cloud

infrastructure through discovery, monitoring, escalation management and automation

Key Result Areas:

Managing continuous integration, continuous deployment and continuous delivery pipeline using Jenkins declarative pipeline

and Build Pipeline Plugins

Supervising different environments on Linux while working on Ansible and using Ansible to manage the deployments to different application servers by writing manifests

Working on data management lifecycle on AZURE blob storage different classes and life cycle rules & on AZURE instances

setup in our dedicated VPC

Monitoring the servers and different services on AWS using cloud watch

Observing the Jenkins builds, environments and troubles hooting the issues in different stages of build and deployment process and have strong administrative experience in Apache tomcat

Maintaining GIT branch, merging and tagging across each production releases and performing dimensions using



Important

Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld.

Jenkins

Continuous Integration using maven Build scripts

Executing ant build scripts from scratch to build java / j2ee application and positioning to multiple tomcat

Supervising the new server build requests, resolving disk space cleaning and subversion access issues and database

activities and enhancing the automated configuration management system

Monitoring Windows and Linux server and troubleshooting the issues

Planning and scheduling the QA, Stage, production deployments, preparing the release schedule and communicating across

different teams

Maintaining autoscale on nodes and pods masterserver and Kubernetes cluster setup

Preparing the images on docker pull the docker hub for required images

Autoscaling Cloud AWS service build Ec2 ELB and backup on AMI snapshot based on requirement; building and maintaining

free service / costless architechure

Forming EKS and maintaining containers on Java application and scaling on nodes; building VPC and configuring private

subnets public subnets which maintain almost all private services

Modifying DNS zone files and managing MX records, Nameservers and Arecords and installing Docker which deploy

server in Docker

Project/Client: Multiple Clients Duration: NoV16 - NoV17

Role: Tools / Onboarding Engineer

Technologies Used:

Operating Systems: Ubuntu 14.04, Ubuntu 18.04
Patch / Monitoring Tool: OpsRamp (formerly known as Vistara IT)
Others: Networking devices, VMI, SNMP, Ubuntu and Hyper-V

Ticketing Tool: NNC (Company Owned)

Virtual Environments: VMware, Hyper-V, XenCenter

Key Result Areas:

Monitored portal using onboard devices

Deployed monitoring tool in customer's environment and configured for the devices Performed troubleshoot related to monitoring tool

Managed OpsRamp portal related issues such as discovery and management, performance graphs, add/remove devices from

monitoring

Worked with tower teams to troubleshoot the issues with respective applications/configurations & OpsRamp support to resolve the OpsRamp portal related issues

Operated on incidents, changes and adhoc customer requests

Created automated jobs for patching, backups and discovery of the devices in the monitoring environment

AKIVNTA Real Estate Broking & Advisory Services Private Limited as Server Administrator Mar 2015 to Aug 2016

Project Executed:

Title: CLRE

Period: Mar'15-Aug'16

Key Result Areas:

Worked on installation and setup of tomcat apache servers and deployment of web application

Created job in Jenkins and automated deployment web application and created VMs in azure

Performed S3 buckets creation and generated policy for the buckets on request basis

Completed monitoring the server health on daily basis daily and managed scheduled jobs using

Scheduled and managed jobs using Cron

Resolved merge conflicts, code check with sonarqube & Jenkins pipeline script and automated infra using Ansible Configured Elastic Load balancer (ELB) such as high availability of ELB using various subnets in various availability

configured security settings and health check for application

Maintained virtual private Clouds (VPC), NAT.; performed S3 buckets creation and policy generation for the buckets

based on

the request

Created and managed elastic Block Storage(EBS) and S3 buckets; gave permission and implemented versioning on S3 buckets

Designed Identity and Access Management (IAM) and CloudWatch to monitor Instance, ELB and EC2's

Installed and configured Red Hat Enterprise Linux servers; monitored server and services, user administration, network configuration of Linux servers

Generated SSH password key

Administered File System and managed such as monitoring various logs, file system sizes

Configured NIC card and troubleshoot on network level issues Installed, updated, inquired and removed software packages with RPM and YUM

Setup the Access Control List (ACL) as per customer requirement and installed & configured FTP Server

Created and maintained users accounts, groups and provided permissions as requested

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Sc (Computers) from Sikkim Manipal University (SMU) in 2013

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Telegu				

DOUGLE TOP

Affirmative Action

Category: **General**Physically Challenged: **No**

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent
Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.